（はがねコテツ）ふわ～
うぐっ あ～
ああ…
（神月かみづきイズモ）
緊張感 なさすぎないか？
Aren't you being a little too laid back?
（コテツ）いや ほら～ ここ最近
Oh, well you know, things were
pretty tense around here recently
砂隠すながくれの里さとでの騒動で
ずっと緊張状態だったろ？
with the incident in the Sand Village.
それも 決着ついたみたいだし
But now that it's been settled...
そしたら どっと疲れが出ちゃってさ
I'm suddenly overcome
with exhaustion...
（イズモ）だからって
いつ 何が起こるか分からないぞ
Even so, we don't know
what's going to happen next.
常に警戒を怠らないことこそ
未然に…
Only by being cautious at all times
are we able to prevent...
（コテツ）そんなに 年中
気を張ってちゃ
You won't last if
you remain cautious at all times.
身が持たんだろ？
ほ～ら リラックス リラックス
Come on, relax, relax!
（犬塚いぬづかキバ）ハハハ…
弱い者いじめは よくねえぞ！
It's not good to tease weak ones.
（奈良ならシカマル）あっ あ～あ
ああ～
（シカマル）昨日 寝る前に
わざわざセットした...
I set the alarm clock
before I went to bed last night,
目覚まし時計より
先に起きちまった
and here, I get up before
the alarm goes off.
なんか 素直にこのベルを
止めるのは納得いかねえ
I can't bring myself to turn off
the alarm.
かといって このままにしてちゃ
But if I don't,
then the annoying ring won't stop.
ずっと 小うるさい音が
鳴りやまねえし
ああ～ こんなこと
考えてることがめんどくせー
It's such a pain just thinking
about this whole thing!
（秋道あきみちチョウジ）お代わり
Seconds!
（イズモ）ん？
（コテツ）なんだ？
What is that?
（マイト･ガイ）うおおお～
どけどけどけ ラストスパート！
Move, move, move!
Last spurt! Goal!
ゴール！
（カカシ）ぬはっ
First place!
１着～！
（コテツ）あ… ああ…
（ロック･リー）うおおお～！
惜しくも２着！
Sadly, second place!
なんの競争です？
- What kind of race is that?
- Beats me...
さあ
いよっと
リーよ まだまだ修業が足りんな
Hey Lee, you need to train more.
はい 次こそ
１着になるように頑張ります
Yes! I will try to be first place next time.
（ガイ）しか～し
ここで 残念な報告がある
But, there is regrettable news.
なっ なんですか？ いったい
Wh-What is it?
（ガイ）リーよ
お前は２着じゃない
Lee, you are not second place.
お前は３着だ！
You are... third place!
ええっ！ あ…
Huh?!
２着は 私が背負っている
このカカシなのだ！
Second place is Kakashi,
who I am carrying!
ヌハハハ…
とんだラッキーマンだな
カカシよ
Kakashi, you are too lucky!
You don't need to thank me.
別に礼はいらんぞ
ぬおおお！
また１つ 先生から
貴重な教訓を得た気がする！
I feel like I learned another
important lesson from you.
（日向ひゅうがネジ）相変わらず
このノリにはついていけん
As usual, I can't keep up
with their craziness.
（テンテン）走っては
ついてきたけどね
Although we did run along after them.
くだらん
Ridiculous!
よし 全員そろったな
Okay, everyone's here, eh?!
では早速 綱手つなで様に報告だ
Then let's go report to
Tsunade-sama right away.
（春野はるのサクラ）あの～ ガイ先生
Um, Guy-sensei...
なんだ？
What is it?
（サクラ）カカシ先生が…
Kakashi-sensei is...
（ガイ）ん？
Huh? Oh!
おお…
こりゃ 報告より病院が先か
Guess it's the hospital before reporting.
（はたけカカシ）ああ…
♪～
You are my friend.
you are my friend
Ah that day's dream...
aa ano hi no yume
You haven't forgotten it, have you?
ima demo mada wasuretenain deshou
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah it had just started your one longest way.
aa hajimatta bakka kimi no one longest way
Woah, I'm starting on a journey now!
woah ima tabidatsu yo
EVERDAY hereafter is a shining day.
everyday kono saki mo shining day
Unchanging singin', a bright morning smile.
kawarazu singin' hikaru asa no smile
This is the last farewell on funny days.
kore de miosame no funny days
Leaping into the future I see. Go far, dream of my heart.
tobidatsu future mezashita go far kokoro no dream of
I'll go the distance, the endless sky is blue.
i'll go the distance mihatenu sora wa blue
I've hitched a ride on the star ship, this is the best forever trip.
norikonda star ship kore ga saigo no forever trip
You are my friend.
you are my friend
Ah that day's dream...
aa ano hi no yume
You haven't forotten it, have you?
ima demo mada wasuretenai deshou
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah, it had just started your one longest way.
aa hajimatta bakka kimi no one longest way
Woah, I'm starting on a journey now!
woah ima tabidatsu yo
Thank you my friend.
thank you my friend
Ah even now,
aa ano hi no koto
I still remember that day.
ima demo mada oboeteru kara
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah those days that will never come back.
aa mou nidoto sou modoranai days
～♪
Woah I'll go the distance!
woah i'll go the distance
The New Target
（カカシ）ん？ あ…
おっ 気がついたぞ
Oh! He's awake!
（カカシ）あ～あ
So I'm back here again...
また ここか
（綱手）ご苦労だったな カカシ
Good job, Kakashi.
（サクラ）師匠！
Master...
Tsunade-sama...
（カカシ）綱手様
あっ…
はっ…
No, Kakashi-sensei!
Don't push yourself.
（サクラ）ダメよ カカシ先生
無理しちゃ
I examined you earlier,
but you need to be in bed for a week.
（綱手）さっき診させてもらったが
１週間はベッドの上だな
任務に復帰するまでには
更に数日かかるだろう
It will take a few more days
until you can return to duty.
（うずまきナルト）くっ…
I guess that's how it goes...
（カカシ）やっぱり そうですか
（綱手）新しい写輪眼を使いこなすには
まだ かかりそうだな
Seems it will still take a while until
you can master the new Sharingan.
（カカシ）ああ… そうですね
Yes...
Just rest. Try not to push
yourself for a while.
（綱手）当分は無理せず
養生することだ
Team Guy should rest today too.
You can turn in the report later.
ガイ班も きょうは休め
報告書は 後日でよい
Yes!
（ガイ）はっ！
Let's go, Shizune.
（綱手）いくぞ シズネ
（シズネ）はい
Yes.
あっ 師匠！
Oh... Master!
（ナルト）ん？
Is it regarding that matter?
（綱手）例の話か？
はい
Yes.
Did you tell Kakashi?
カカシには話したのか？
Since Kakashi-sensei has been
like that all this time, I haven't yet...
カカシ先生は ずっと
あの状態でしたから… まだ
How about Naruto?
ナルトには？
あ…
師匠に相談してからでないと
と思って
I thought I should first consult you...
Give me the details.
（綱手）詳しく聞こう
（サクラ）暁あかつきのメンバーの１人
サソリから得た情報です
It's what I heard from
the Akatsuki member, Sasori.
He said it was a reward for beating him...
自分を倒した褒美だと言って
（サソリ）草隠くさがくれの里さとにある天地橋てんちきょうに…
In ten days,
go to the Tenchi Bridge
located in the Village Hidden
in the Grass at high noon.
10日後の真昼に行け
I've got a spy working as one of
Orochimaru's subordinates...
大蛇丸おろちまるの部下に俺のスパイがいる
そこで そいつと落ち合うことに…
I was supposed to rendezvous...
with him... there...
なってる…
In ten days... at Tenchi Bridge, huh...
10日後 天地橋か
あれから４日たっているんで
６日後ということになりますが
Four days have passed,
so it will be in six days.
信用できるのか？
Can you trust your source?
状況から考えて信じてよいかと
Considering the situation,
it's safe to say we can trust it.
What would you do if it were a trap?
（綱手）ワナだったらどうする？
（サクラ）あ…
There is a possibility that
Orochimaru is just bait,
（綱手）大蛇丸は餌で
暁が その天地橋で
待ち伏せしている可能性だってある
and the Akatsuki will
be waiting there.
If it is a trap,
I'll fight with all my might!
ワナなら… 戦うだけです
戦うといっても カカシは
あと１週間以上は あのザマだ
Fight? Kakashi will be in bed
for more than a week.
しかし もう６日しかない
But we only have six days left.
そもそもカカシ班は
For that matter,
ever since Sasuke left,
Team Kakashi has been short on staff.
サスケがいなくなった時点で
班員割れを起こしている
Yes...
はい
（綱手）メンバーを補充して
新しいチームを編成するしかないな
We can only add another member
and create a new team.
（シズネ）綱手様
（サクラ）あ…
Tsunade-sama!
What is it?
なんだ？
それなら 別の小隊を送り
様子を見るべきです
Then, you should send a different unit
to investigate the situation.
百歩譲って
サクラを行かせたとしても
Even if you let Sakura go,
you should leave out Naruto!
ナルト君は外すべきです
えっ？
Shizune...
（綱手）シズネ
Yes.
はい
（綱手）サクラは お前同様
私が心から信用できる数少ない忍しのびだ
Like you, Sakura is
one of the few shinobi
whom I can trust from
the bottom of my heart.
この任務は 必ず
サクラのいるカカシ班に行かせる
I will definitely let Team Kakashi go,
mostly because Sakura is on it.
（シズネ）それなら私の隊が行っても
同じじゃないですか
Wouldn't it be the same
if my team went?
（綱手）同じではない
It's not the same!
Sakura and Naruto are both
desperately trying
サクラもナルトも
かつての仲間だったサスケを
必死になって追っている
to seek out Sasuke,
their former teammate...
サスケを助けたいと
誰よりも強く思っている
They wish to save Sasuke
more than anyone.
その強い思いが任務を成功に導く
That strong desire will
lead the mission to success.
You and Sakura are different...
お前とサクラとは違う
I understand, but,
for this mission, Naruto-kun should...
分かりました
でもナルト君は この任務…
この話を聞いた以上
Now that he's heard this...
what would Naruto say?
ナルトがなんて言うかな？
えっ？
Let's search for our new team
member immediately!
（ナルト）早速
メンバー探しだってばよ！
（サクラ）あっ
（シズネ）ああっ
（綱手）フフッ
んじゃ！
Later!
（綱手）ったく あのせっかちが
Sheesh, that impatient brat...
I wasn't done talking yet.
まだ話の途中だってえのに
（綱手）あいつには
不思議な力があってな
He has a mysterious power...
みんな あいつに賭けてみたくなるのさ
Everyone... starts wanting
to place their bets on him.
（ナルト）火影(ほかげ)は…
Becoming Hokage...
becoming Hokage is my dream...!
火影は 俺の夢だから！
The child who was entrusted
with the First Lord's necklace...
（シズネ）あの初代様の
首飾りを託された子
Indeed, Naruto-kun might not
be an ordinary kid.
ナルト君は 本当に
普通の子じゃないのかもしれない
（ナルト）サスケ…
Sasuke...
（ナルト）う～ん 誰がいっかなあ
Hmm, who might be good?
ここは 慎重に慎重に考えなきゃな
I need to think about this
very carefully.
下手に選んで
俺の足手まといになったら
It would be a pain
if I mistakenly choose someone
who would slow me down.
かなわねえからなあ
それに 実力はあっても
性格に問題があっちゃあ
Plus, even if the person is skillful,
there might be a problem
with their personality,
チームワークが
台なしになっちまうし
and that will ruin the teamwork.
サクラちゃん面くいだから
And Sakura-chan is a sucker
for handsome boys,
あんまりルックスがよすぎんのも
危ねえしなあ
so it would be dangerous
if he were too good-looking.
う～ん 悩むなあ
This is hard.
（油女あぶらめシノ）久しぶりだな ナルト
Long time no see, Naruto.
（ナルト）あ？
Huh?
誰？
Who are you?
（シノ）俺だ
It's me.
（ナルト）んん？
Huh?
（ナルト）ん？
ああ あ～！
あ～ え～っと…
（シノ）久しぶりに会ったとしても
Even though we haven't
seen each other for a long time,
仲間の顔ぐらいは覚えておくものだ
you should remember
your comrade's face.
なぜなら
Because the one that spoke
to you will feel bad.
話しかけた側が
つらいことになるからだ
そっ そのクソ面倒くさ～いしゃべり方は
Oh... um... that really indirect speech...
could it be...?
もしかして…
シノ！
Shino!
（シノ）やっと思い出したか
You finally remembered.
（ナルト）ぐぐ…
そんだけ顔を隠してりゃ
誰だって分かんねえってばよ
If you cover up that much,
no one will know--
（ナルト）な…
ん…
（キバ）シノ はえ～じゃねえの
Shino, you're here early!
ん？
ああ！ キバか？
Are you Kiba?
おお～！
Oh!
よっ！
ハハッ
やっぱナルトじゃねえか
このにおいはよ
This smell! It is Naruto!
ハハハ… 俺って気づいたの
そこなのかよ
You knew it was me 'cause of that?
（ナルト）えっ？
その犬ってば もしかして
That dog, could it be...
（キバ）な～に言ってんだ
赤丸あかまるに決まってんだろ
What are you talking about?
Of course, it's Akamaru!
（ナルト）ええ～！
Huh?!
っつうか お前
デカくなったんじゃねえか？ おい
Hey, did you grow?!
いやいや… デカくなったのは
赤丸だってばよ
Naw, naw, naw...
Akamaru is the one that grew.
犬って 短期間で
そんなにデカくなる動物なのか？
Do dogs become that big
in such a short amount of time?
そうか？
Really? Since we're always together,
I can't really tell.
いつも一緒にいっから
あんまり分かんねえけどな
ぐわ… いや 気づけってばよ
Can't tell?! That Akamaru,
he used to be on your head!
昔は お前の頭の上に
乗っかってたんだぞ 赤丸
そうだよな シノ
Right, Shino?!
ん？
（シノ）キバには
すぐ気づいたものだな ナルト
Seems like you noticed Kiba right away,
didn't you, Naruto?
（ナルト）ぐ…
ヤベえ すねてる
Oh shoot, he's upset.
（日向ひゅうがヒナタ）あっ…
（ナルト）ん？
Na-!
（ヒナタ）ナ… ナルト君？
N-Naruto-kun...
（ヒナタ）里に戻ってきていたとは
聞いていたけど
I heard that he came back
to the village.
Wh-What should I do?
ど… どうしよう
心の準備が…
I'm not ready yet since we haven't
seen each other for a while.
しばらく会ってなかったから
なんて話しかけたら…
What should I say...?
えっと…
Um... Um...
なんだ ヒナタか
Oh, it's Hinata!
（ヒナタ）あっ！
（ナルト）何 隠れてんだってばよ
Why are you hiding?
（ヒナタ）あ…
（ナルト）あああ…
あらっ ヒナタ？
Huh?! Hinata.
なあヒナタ おい！
おい ヒナタ！
Hey, Hinata, hey, Hinata!
（キバ）ああもう なんでお前は
いつもナルト見て気絶するんだよ
Why do you always faint
after seeing Naruto?
頼む どうしても新しいメンバーが
必要なんだってばよ
Please! We need a new member!
（ヒナタ）あれっ？
Huh?
タイミングが悪かったな
俺たちも ちょうど任務が入って
You came at the wrong time,
we just got a mission and
we're waiting for Kurenai-sensei.
ここで 紅くれない先生と
待ち合わせしているところだ
（鼓動）
（ヒナタ）あっ 私 いったい…
What... I...?
（ナルト）でもさ お前んとこは
赤丸もいるわけだし
But you have Akamaru,
so lend us one person.
１人貸してくれればいいってばよ
なあ キバ
Come on, Kiba?
（鼓動）
（ヒナタ）どうしちゃったんだろう
What happened...?
（キバ）ああもう むちゃ言うな！
What are you talking about?!
俺が一緒に行かねえと
赤丸とのコンビ技が使えねえだろ
If I don't go I can't use
the combo attack with Akamaru!
（鼓動）
（ヒナタ）そっか
Oh yeah, I met Naruto-kun and...
ナルト君と久しぶりに会って
（ナルト）いや そうだよな
Oh that's right.
Then, then...
あ～ それじゃあ それじゃあ…
あっ シノは…
Hey, Shino is...
（シノ）ヒナタにも
すぐ気づいたものだな ナルト
You noticed Hinata
right away too, Naruto.
（ナルト）んが…
（ナルト）まだすねてる
He is still sulking...
（ナルト）チェッ もういいよ！
Forget it!
You guys are all lousy friends!
友達がいのないヤツばっかだぜ！
（ヒナタ）ナルト君の声
Naruto's voice...
ヒナタ！ 黙って
俺についてこいってばよ！
Hinata! Just shut up and
come with me!
（ヒナタ）黙ってついてこいって
そんな…
"Just shut up and come with me"...?
No way... no way... so suddenly...
そんな いきなり
（ナルト）あ？
結局 断られちまったなあ
After all that fuss, I still got rejected.
こうなりゃ あとは…
In that case...
I guess I'll ask those guys.
あいつらに当たってみるか
（キバ）お～い ヒナタ
もうすぐ紅先生が来るぞ
Hey, Hinata, Kurenai-sensei
is going to be here soon. Wake up!
起きろ！
ああもう おい シノ
水 持ってないか？ 水！
Hey, Shino! Do you have water?
Water!
（シノ）空が青いな
The sky... is blue.
ったく だから言ったろ
I told you already, haven't I?
めんどくせーけど 俺は
中忍試験ちゅうにんしけんの係員 任されてんだよ
It's annoying, but I'm in charge
of the Chunin Exam.
まっ そりゃあ お前とは腐れ縁だし
協力はしてやりてえが
I mean, yeah, we have
a long history together,
so I want to lend a hand.
勝手できる立場じゃあねんだよ 俺も
But I'm not in a position
to do whatever I want.
（ナルト）う～ん…
（シカマル）任命したのは五代目だ
The Fifth appointed me,
so she will kill me if I reject the offer.
いまさら断ったりしたら
なんて言われるか
はあ～
女の小言は母ちゃんだけで十分だ
I get scolded enough by my mother.
（ナルト）あ～
せっかくさ～ シカマルならってさ～
頼りにしてたのにさ～
And here I was thinking
"I can count on Shikamaru",
but you go on talking like
it's so annoying and all...
そんな面倒くさそうな顔してさ～
そんな捨て犬みたいな目したって
無理なもんは無理なんだよ
Even if you look at me
with those puppy eyes,
what's impossible is impossible.
（チョウジ）そんなら僕が協力するよ
Then I will lend a hand!
（シカマル･ナルト）ん？
（チョウジ）ほい シカマル
Here! Shikamaru.
これ おばちゃんに頼まれた弁当
This is the lunch box that
your mom asked me to hand you.
（ナルト）チョウジ
Choji!
おいチョウジ お前
そんな勝手なこと言っていいのか？
Hey Choji, are you sure you can say
such an irresponsible thing?
アスマとか いのとの任務が
入ってんじゃねえのかよ
Don't you have a mission
with Asuma and Ino?
（チョウジ）ナルトの話も
このまま放っとけないしさ
I can't ignore what Naruto is saying.
フフッ
アスマ先生と相談してみるよ
I will try to discuss it
with Asuma-sensei.
チョウジ サンキュー！
Choji, thanks!
（シカマル）だから
アスマに言ってもダメなんだって
It's not going to help
if you tell Asuma because
he works under Tsunade-sama.
その上が あの綱手様なんだから
まあ 一応 話してみるよ
Well, I will try to talk to him.
Here's the lunch box.
はい 弁当
（ナルト）おお サンキュー！
Oh! Thanks!
おいナルト それ俺の弁当
Hey, Naruto...
That's my lunch box.
（ナルト）へえ ヘヘヘッ
相変わらず食ってばっかだな
Just like always,
you're still eating, huh?
お前 昔よりデブ…
You... are fatter than before...
（チョウジ）うっ
（シカマル）あっ
Oh!
（ナルト）なっ…
（ナルト）くっ…
（チョウジ）う～！
（ナルト）うっ
（チョウジ）とりゃ～！
シカマル 後ろ！
Shikamaru! Behind!
（シカマル）うっ
（ナルト）おっ
（シカマル）フッ
（チョウジ）フフンッ
（シカマル）あそこか
Over there, huh...?
I haven't seen him before,
but he wears a Leaf head band.
見たことねえヤツだけど
木こノ葉はの額当ひたいあてしてるぞ！
いきなりだな
It was so sudden...
I don't know what he is aiming for,
but we need to capture him and...
何 狙ってるか知らねえが
ああいう手合いは とっ捕まえて…
give him to the Interrogation Unit!
尋問部隊に引き渡す！
I'll assist you! Go Naruto!
援護する いけナルト！
（ナルト）おお！
Right!
Ninja Art: Super Beast Scroll.
（サイ）忍法 超獣偽画ちょうじゅうぎが
（ナルト）うっ
♪～
Reach for it, reach for it, far away.
todoke todoke tooku e
Now I trust these revived tears to you.
ima wo kishikaisei namida azukete
It begins.
hajimare
A long, long story about you
nagai nagai kimi monogatari
"Tears", "tears".
namidatte namidatte
I want to shed them in happy times
ureshii toki ni nagashitai
So what if I want them to float in pretty puddles?
kirei na mizutamari ukabetai no wa nani
The southern sky,
minami no sora ni
It twinkles.
matataiteiru
From all of the stars meeting.
hoshi no kazu hodo no deai kara
Learning about love, receiving a map.
ai wo manandari chizu wo morattari
Are connected.
tsunagatteku
Reach for it, reach for it, far away.
todoke todoke tooku e
Now I trust these revived tears to you.
ima wo kishikaisei namida azukete
Someday a new page will turn.
itsuka mekuru peeji ni
I'm sure it'll be filled with lots of people
kitto takusan no hito ga afureru
It begins,
hajimare
～♪
A long, long story about you.
nagai nagai kimi monogatari
Next Episode
Indeed, Naruto is a Jinchuriki.
確かにナルトは人柱力じんちゅうりきだ
There is no guarantee that the Akatsuki
who seeks Naruto's Nine-Tailed Beast
ナルトから九尾きゅうびを奪った暁が
木ノ葉にとって より大きな災いに
ならないという保証はない
won't become a huge disaster
for the Hidden Leaf.
However, Naruto will someday become
a valuable Ninja to the Hidden Leaf Village.
しかしナルトは いずれ
木ノ葉の大きな戦力となる忍
If perchance, the Hidden Leaf Village
and the Land of Fire
万一 木ノ葉隠れと火の国が
become endangered by my decision,
私の判断ミスのせいで
危機になったのなら
then as the Fifth Hokage,
I will protect them with my life!
命懸けで守ってみせるさ
五代目火影としてな！
Next Time: Formation! New Team Kakashi!
次回「結成！
新カカシ班」
Formation! New Team Kakashi
Wow. It's been a long time
since we saw Naruto.
（キバ）いやあ
久しぶりだったな ナルトのヤツ
うん ちょっと雰囲気
変わったかも
Yeah, he seems a little different.
Really? Well, he grew taller.
そうか？
ああ 背は伸びてたけどよ
It has been two and a half years...
もう２年半だもんね
I've grown taller
since that time too.
私も あのころよりは
背 伸びたもの
Do I look a bit more mature?
ちょっとは大人っぽくなったかな？
Naw, you don't look that different.
（キバ）いや
あんま変わってねえな
What?!
えっ！
（キバ）そうやって
モジモジしてるとこなんか
The fact that you're fidgety
is still the same.
昔のまんまだぜ
No way...
そんなあ
まあ そこいくと俺なんか
前よりもワイルドになったろ？
Well, if you talk about me...
Aren't I wilder than before?
キバ君も
そんなに変わってないと思う…
I don't think you have changed either.
Oh yeah, well...
（キバ）そういや ヒナタは
The way you faint when you see
Naruto hasn't changed either.
ナルト見ると気絶するとこも
変わってねえよな
Ah... well... I was not prepared...
（ヒナタ）あっ あれは心の準備が
Hey, Naruto.
よう ナルト！
あっ
Just kidding.
（キバ）なんてな
（ヒナタ）もう キバ君！
Gosh! Kiba-kun!
ヘヘッ わりい わりい
Sorry, sorry.
（シノ）お前たち
（キバ･ヒナタ）ん？
Hey, you guys.
— Huh?
Shouldn't you acknowledge my existence?
（シノ）そろそろ
俺の存在に気づくべきだ
Because I'm also part of Team Kurenai.
なぜなら 俺も同じ紅班だからだ
シノ君
Shino-kun...
またすねてるよ
He's sulking again.